LeRon Jackson.com

Atlanta, GA 30331 - HireMe@LeRonJackson.com - Linkedin.com/in/LeRonJackson - Github.com/LeRonj23

Business Analysis - IT Management - Web / App Product Development - Product Management

I'm a solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environments, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using **Front End** and **Back End** web technologies. Able to translate solutions into code and work across many different **APIs**, third-party integrations and databases. Exceptional communicator and leader skilled in building and strengthening relationships across company lines to drive cohesive, strategic processes and results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Proficient: Html, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, APIs, AJAX, JSON, XML, MySQL, SQL, Relational Databases
- Knowledge: Firebase, IOS, Swift, Android, Java, Ecommerce, Social Media, Scrum, Agile
- Software: Jira, Kanban, AEM, CQ5, Git, GitHub, Google Analytics, Google Tag Management

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

GhostedBy - https://ghostedbybeta.herokuapp.com

If you have ever been on an interview and never heard back from the company, then you've been GhostedBy! Submit companies to the GhostedBy database with integrity and honesty as this is intended to be a source for candidates to share and research company activities for a more productive job search.

Development (JavaScript, React, Express, Node, Mongoose, MongoDB, Bootstrap, NPM)

Google Books Search - https://github.com/leronj23/Google-Books-Search

This app uses the Google Books API to allow users to search for books and view them in the Google Play store. You can also save books to a list for future reference.

Development (JavaScript, React, Express, Node, Mongoose, MongoDB, Bootstrap, NPM)

Mongo Scraper - https://github.com/leronj23/Mongo-Scraper

This is a web application that scrapes the New York Times Sports sections of their website. The app was made primarily using Mongoose, MongoDB and Cheerio technologies.

Development (JavaScript, Express, Node, Handlebars, NPM, Heroku, MongoDB, Mongoose, Cheerio, Axios)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst / AEM Content Manager – Contractor

August 2018 – Present

American Cancer Society - Atlanta, GA

Perform requirement analysis by gathering and writing user stories for Functional requirements based on interactions with stakeholders for both mobile and web development.

- Scrum Agenda: Facilitate daily elaboration meetings that consist of web developers, product and project management, and QA teams. Removed any impediments by requesting off-line meetings for discussion. Managed backlog, prioritized bugs, and QA reviews. Monitored and tracked all Azure (TFS) tickets for all projects in an Agile environment.
- **Web Content:** Make content changes and updates in **AEM** content management system for Cancer.org. Recommended UX/UI changes as needed for all web page creation.

Sr. Operations Manager – Contractor

July 2017 - March 2018

Turner Broadcasting - Atlanta, GA

Responsible for the daily operational, support, and success of the NBA's website NBA.com, which included new products and features.

- **NBA project:** Created the launch plan for the NBA Pre-Season and Regular Season schedule release. Coordinated with mobile, web, and connected devices product managers for a seamless launched of data feed for their respected devices.
- Technical Troubleshooting: Reported any website issue in Jira by writing technical requirements to help re-engineer any
 problem.
- Scrum Agenda: Facilitated daily scrum meetings that consist of 4-6 web developers, product and project management, QA, and occasional stakeholders. Removed any impediments by requesting off-line meetings for discussion. Organized sprint planning,

managed backlog, prioritized bugs, QA reviews, retrospectives, and demos to stakeholders. Monitored and tracked all Jira ticket statuses with Kanban. Held weekly meetings with stakeholder for status on the project.

Sr. Manager Business Analyst Ecommerce Sales and Marketing – Contractor

April 2014 - December 2016

AT&T - Atlanta, GA

Tasked with orchestrating ecommerce strategy, digital ads, mobile ad integration, and business solutions to facilitate online transactions. Translated and wrote business requirements into effective UI experiences for customers utilizing mobile and website touch points. Managed projects through full lifecycle utilizing Agile methodologies. Trained employees on use of IT tools and processes and resolved escalated technical issues.

- **Web Presence Integration:** Managed website and mobile app ad integration for all digital ads for AT&T U-verse and DirecTV products. Monitored ecommerce merchandising for all home services, e.g., internet, home phone, and cable.
- Legal Disclaimer projects: Launched Legal Disclaimer Repository project in CQ5/AEM content management system bringing Uverse and DIRECTV products in compliance with Federal Trade Commission. Transitioned legal disclaimers from DirecTV.com to AT&T.com. Responsible for all legal content for U-verse and DIRECTV products.
- **Technical Troubleshooting:** Developed and implemented testing and conducted **A/B testing** to maximize click through rates, troubleshot Html and CSS code issues, and resolved **CQ5/AEM** content management system implementation errors, website and mobile layout misalignments, and content changes.

Technical Operations Analyst

July 2013 - February 2014

360i - Atlanta, GA

Directly collaborated with Account Management, Media, Ad Operations, Advanced Analytics, and clients facilitating daily operations for Capital One and Equifax. Tested and validated 3rd party tracking pixels for implementation on all campaigns and mobile app integration. Partnered with Account Operations Manager to ensure flawless execution of campaigns.

- **Process Optimization:** Member of DART Governance/DoubleClick processes for Capital One/Equifax to ensure clarity and transparency, and share expertise in technical application, ad serving technologies, and tagging implementation.
- Quality Assurance: Owned QA process while supporting Media and Display team in implementation and integration of piggyback pixels from 3rd party vendors.

Ad Operations Analyst Lead - Ecommerce

September 2011 - February 2014

Travelocity.com - Dallas, TX

Implemented, supported and managed all advertising campaigns through full lifecycles for clients across websites, languages, and mobile devices. Expertly analyzed and monitored success rates. Directly liaised with key leadership to recommend campaign modifications and optimize performance in alignment with requirements. Conducted testing and analyzed results to implement critical updates. Executed webpage project management and utilized Agile methodology throughout all phases. Scheduled and reported status updates to key stakeholders.

- **Technical Troubleshooting:** Proactively communicated with Google, Inc to troubleshoot issues, and update APIs for DoubleClick server upgrades. Orchestrated Google, Inc. server updates in alignment with business requirements.
- Pricing Management: Provided critical timely and confidential pricing updates for CPM, CPA, CPL, and CPC.

EDUCATION

Information Technology – Concentration Georgia Perimeter College

Business Administration – Concentration
University of Nebraska at Omaha

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Web Developer Certification Georgia Institution of Technology

Scrum Master Certification
Scrum Alliance